<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mere Code - Comments: And then what?</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://code.mumak.net/feeds/comment.and-then-what.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><updated>2010-11-19T00:39:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Posted by: jml (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/#comment-2308328177472353504.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-16T17:52:00+00:00</updated><author><name>jml (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2010-11-16:2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sense, it'll be a long time before the Canonical team works on proper
Semantic stuff for Launchpad, but we'd be open to contributions. If
you're interested, you might want to talk to the FusionForge guys about
it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; we do the issue tracker work, we'll definitely consider those
cases. Some folk want to merge Answers in too. There are a lot of traps
here, so we're going to have to be careful.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better project roles is a longstanding issue and I agree it should be
fixed. Thanks for the reminder.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been thinking a little bit recently about how to group projects
together better on Launchpad, but I don't think we had put Ubuntu into
the mix. (I'm reminded of &lt;a href="http://mdzlog.alcor.net/2010/11/15/ubuntu-project-platform-products/"&gt;mdz's product, platform, project
post&lt;/a&gt;).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex, glad you like it :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: jelmer (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/#comment-3562104730001630838.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-16T15:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>jelmer (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2010-11-16:2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To me, Launchpad provides a structured view of the very diverse free
software world, with a flat namespace. No matter what the upstream
project uses Launchpad can provide me the source code, the bugs, the
Ubuntu packages and the translations for that project and allow me to
use the same tools I use for all other projects too. This is a unique
thing about Launchpad, it's what makes it so great for people who hack
on multiple projects (like packagers).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for other version control systems seems like a great thing to
support. I'm biased here, but rather than allowing plain hosting of
every possible DVCS as e.g. SourceForge provides it would be nice if
Launchpad could maintain its tight integration. Perhaps I'm biased here,
but I'd like to see Launchpad e.g. support Subversion's mod_dav
protocol on top of Bazaar repositories, much like GitHub does on top of
Git repositories (https://github.com/blog/626-announcing-svn-support).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a proper dashboard would be a really great addition I think.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: jml (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/#comment-4060493401200002983.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-16T15:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>jml (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2010-11-16:2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Jelmer,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fully agree. If Launchpad ever provided support for other VCS clients,
it would have to be in such a way that you could still use Bazaar
regardless of the project.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporting VCS-specific protocols on top of Bazaar repos seems like the
ideal way of doing that. But you would certainly know better than I :)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jml&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: Sense Hofstede (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/#comment-5016531907366722606.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-16T16:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sense Hofstede (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2010-11-16:2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first thing I think after reading this post is: great work,
Launchpad Team! You've been doing an awesome job and if you look at
where Launchpad came from, so much has been improved.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I am a bit of a semantic web fan, and I would love
to see more semantics coming to Launchpad, but I understand there are
more important things.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things you mention in your post look great, and I agree with your
plans to (somewhat) merge Blueprints and Bugs. Changing the name of the
bug tracker to Issue Tracker would already be an improvement, because it
would be more inclusive and describe better the possible uses of the
tracker.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because bug tracking is being used for more things than just plain
software bugs. There is a Launchpad project that contains bug reports
concerning community issues. Many LoCos, including mine, use Launchpad
to manage tasks in the bug tracker. The most notable example, though,
would be the One Hundred Paper Cuts project. It is used for reporting
bugs that are in fact mostly usability issues. They require a bit more
discussion and are not (always) exactly bugs. (More information about
what constitutes a paper cut can be found at .)&lt;br /&gt;
It would be great if these other uses of the bug/issue tracker would be
considered during the design of the (partial?) merge of the blueprint
and bug trackers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue we see is the fact that the Ubuntu community and Canonical
created several different projects on Launchpad to manage subprojects of
the Ubuntu project. It is not possible to make a link between the
'ubuntu' distribution type project on Launchpad and its subprojects,
like 'ubuntu-community', 'hundredpapercuts' and others. This has the
consequence that the 'ubuntu' project on Launchpad only contains bugs
and source and translations of the packages in the main repositories.
But there is more to the project! It would be great if Launchpad could
make the other aspects of the community more visible by allowing to link
projects together.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that something else that would increase clarity and make the
project pages on Launchpad more useful would be displaying roles on the
front and section pages. Currently Launchpad already has some roles
displayed (Driver, Maintainer, Bug Supervisor and such), but these are
limited and do not cover the full community. Instead, or in addition to
this, Launchpad could allow projects to create roles/functions (with a
unique (per-project) slug for API authentication purposes) and assign
teams or persons to it. This would give visitors (and, if the proper
semantics would be used, also bots ;)) a way to find out who is
responsible for what and contact them and. be an authoritative source
for this kind of information.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you would do away with the set roles that give permissions,
like Driver or Maintainer, you could create a much more flexible
permission system by allowing project maintainers to assign capabilities
to roles. Instead of the Bug Supervisor being shown at the bug tracker
page, you would see the roles that have bug-related capabilities there.
This would allow every project to complete customise its permissions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially now Launchpad is used more and more as a provider for
authentication and permissions such a system would increase Launchpad's
value as a platform to offer this information.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some ideas that came up in me/I remembered. I hope you like
them, or at least that they help you with getting (even more!) ideas for
Launchpad's future.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: sourcefrog (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/#comment-8754280189929779115.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-19T00:39:00+00:00</updated><author><name>sourcefrog (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2010-11-19:2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great post!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to see a dashboard/notifications/wall type feature.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: alexlauni (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2010/11/and-then-what.html/#comment-9156846502849770775.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-16T16:19:00+00:00</updated><author><name>alexlauni (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2010-11-16:2010/11/and-then-what.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Am I dreaming? I agree 100% with the other comments with respect to vcs
support. Bzr is pretty fast on top of git and svn already. Maybe a
git-bzr bridge for users of git to talk to bzr repos, but keeping
launchpad standardized on bzr is a good choice.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dashboard and issue tracker things sound like a dream come true.
Please steal me from DX to work on this ;)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>