<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mere Code - Comments: Meta-meeting stuff</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://code.mumak.net/feeds/comment.meta-meeting-stuff.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://code.mumak.net/2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/</id><updated>2009-10-09T09:41:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Posted by: spiv (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/#comment-3306118758545015894.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-09T05:35:00+01:00</updated><author><name>spiv (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2009-10-09:2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wonder what to do about the "laptops not closed" problem. I guess the
solution depends on the cause...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Email genuinely backing up and needs to be dealt with?&lt;/em&gt; That certainly
sounds plausible after several days. Allocate some time for catching up
on demands from the outside world.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meeting fatigue — after several days of intense discussion perhaps some
people's capacity for engaging in intense discussion is simply
exhausted?&lt;/em&gt; Not sure what to do about this except for taking more time
or doing less, neither of which is satisfactory. Or finding a way when
planning the week to accomodate the inevitable reduced energy towards
the end, e.g. shorter sessions and more breaks?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some participants don't think the current topic is very relevant to
them, or that their involvement is superfluous?&lt;/em&gt; There's a pretty
important disconnect there... why did they attend in the first place,
and why were they invited? If circumstances have changed since the
meeting attendees were chosen then maybe there needs to be a way for
people to gracefully uninvite themselves.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put another way, if someone's laptop is not closed, why don't they just
excuse themselves and leave the room entirely? Perhaps there's no just
obvious way to do that politely. Or perhaps they feel obliged to be
there, but simultaneously don't agree that it's a good use of their time
(maybe just because they have meeting fatigue). That's a pretty serious
problem, and definitely a vibe-sucking one, and I'd love to know a good
solution.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe next time quietly approach a culprit during a break and ask them
as non-judgementally as possible why they've started opening their
laptop during a meeting?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: jml (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/#comment-8184614873894207045.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-09T09:41:00+01:00</updated><author><name>jml (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2009-10-09:2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FWIW, we deliberately scheduled an hour of "unstructured" time into each
day.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary, although I can't speak for the others, you describe exactly how
I've felt at these things in the past, and yes, it is draining. Although
I can't think of any right now, perhaps there are more considerate ways
of handling this than opening up your laptop.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I also had my laptop open inappropriately at some
points of the meeting, and bear absolutely no ill will towards anyone
there who did the same.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: Mary (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/#comment-8499344312809381468.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-09T08:46:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mary (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2009-10-09:2009/10/meta-meeting-stuff.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Re email checking, I don't know exactly how you set it up, but maybe
there's an introversion problem with these sprint meetings.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get a bunch of people, many of whom (I think) work from home.
They've travelled, they might be sharing a hotel room, they're spending
all day having high stakes, high bandwidth face-to-face interactions.
They socialise all evening. They sleep. They go round again. It may be
pretty draining especially compared to their usual quota of human
interaction.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it may be that some of them are trying to create some downtime for
themselves by laptopping. I don't have a good solution given the expense
of these meetings.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>