<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mere Code - Comments: Review Thoughts</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://code.mumak.net/feeds/comment.review-thoughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><updated>2008-11-17T22:24:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Posted by: jml (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-2560779994666102914.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-17T22:24:00+00:00</updated><author><name>jml (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-17:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, glyph, vague comments do have *something* to do with the tools,
because with some technologies it's easier to be specific. Email quoted
reply, for example.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have anything as good as "jump to an FQPN". I do have etags
though, which is generally good enough.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own toolchain for navigating big emails could probably be better. At
the moment I use Gmail's "collapse quoted text" feature and that solves
most of my problems.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big advantage of email (which you could get from other tools,
I guess) is that as the *reviewer* I can easily see which of my points
the author has replied to, and more importantly, which points they
haven't.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other points worth mentioning is that Launchpad tries to keep diff size
down (you need to specially arrange a reviewer if your diff is &gt; 800
lines). This probably has an impact on tool experience.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree that something higher level would be much better. Perhaps we can
con Barry into writing such an emacs mode?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: Benjamin (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-2644289410147888005.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-15T16:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benjamin (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-15:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You might be interested in Guido van Rossum's Rietveld. [1] You just add
the URL of your SVN repo, submit a patch, and tada: inline comment
reviews. We've been using quite happily with core Python dev. The only
annoying thing is posting your patch to the bug tracker and Rietveld,
but that could be negated with Trac integration.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] http://codereview.appspot.com&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: intellectronica (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-299545788632170089.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-15T23:52:00+00:00</updated><author><name>intellectronica (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-15:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I agree, and I hope that as the review facilities in LP evolve, we'll
grow something that leads users in this direction. One of the things I
really like about Launchpad is the (implicit, but nevertheless very
clear) approach of building an opinionated tool, a
there-is-only-one-way-to-do-it tool. Once we've identified a process
that works very well we should make Launchpad support this process and
no other. I don't know if Rietveld is the answer, but I hope that
eventually we'll have some kind of rich review tool that helps you do
the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: glyph (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-3762152742188556017.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-16T01:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>glyph (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-16:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel like these are all kind of sad little workarounds for what I
believe we all really want.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm going to review a branch, I want to get a side-by-side diff
view &lt;em&gt;where I actually write code&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. Emacs, that looks something
like Meld. I want to have the merged code in my working copy so that I
can run unit tests locally. Ideally, I'd like to have that same UI for
transparently running the code on the buildbots as well, but we're
getting pretty far afield into fantasy at that point...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to annotate the changes by indicating them directly
and typing them next to the changed region of code. Then, when I'm done
writing comments... I just want to push a button and send the review! I
don't want to screw around with my mail client, push buttons on a web
page, or anything like that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guido's code review stuff (is codereview.appspot.com the same as
Rietveld?) and reviewboard both kinda-sorta get this done, but with a
god-awful amount of mousing around. The "Show 10 Above / Show 10 Below"
thing on codereview.appspot.com is a hilarious example of how bad this
gets. I don't want to see "10 more lines" of diff, I want to know what
goddamn class definition this method is a part of!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything that involves chopping up unstructured unified-diff content and
reading it or writing about it is sucky. Anything that separates the
code from the diff from the ticket from the review is sucky. I can
definitely see the advantages of doing things the Canonical way, but I
can also see the immense disadvantages of trying to cram the immense
suckage of email into the already sucky world of code review.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally an emerging feature I like about Twisted's review process is
that reviewers are starting to use enumerated lists rather than bullet
points, so it's easy to refer to a point in subsequent comments and
re-reviews. But, in the system I'd really like to be using, that would
all be automatic.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: jml (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-6598108978451585050.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-16T02:11:00+00:00</updated><author><name>jml (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-16:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;glyph, certainly the diff format has a lot of problems and using
something richer that could provide more context would be better.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But regarding cramming "the immense suckage of email into the already
sucky world of code review", I think you'd be surprised. By and large,
we find doing reviews email &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; sucky.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason is that you get a diff and a cover letter in your
inbox, you type your recommended changes next to the code that causes
them, then push a button that sends a review. It really is quite close
to what you describe in paragraph 3.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that using numbers rather than bullets is definitely an
improvement, but you get essentially that for free with email quoting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can, you should contrive a way to experiment with doing reviews
by email.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, fwiw, I'm not sure this is a Canonical-wide thing. I think
Landscape uses a system much more like Twisted's, for example.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: glyph (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-8355321387342363380.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-17T01:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>glyph (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-17:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There were a few things that I realize were implicit in my last comment.
For one thing, I didn't make it clear how much I agree with the
experience you're espousing. I always copy review comments into an
outline buffer and delete each point as I deal with it, using it as a
nice to-do list with a built in progress meter. I actually find that
emailed diffs make this much harder to do.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also offered no specific criticism of the suckage of email and diffs.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find scrolling around hundreds of lines of un-annotated context
difficult, and (without reconfiguring my editor to use extremely loud
font faces) I find it easy to miss individual points, and I spend a lot
more time reading code that I wrote. I also find it very easy to get a
hunk of diff and have no idea what chunk of code it refers to without
scrolling around. Even without my aforementioned elisp, I find it a lot
easier to manually translate the string
"twisted.web.server.Request.render" into some file/line pair in my
editor than "@@ -187,7 +187,7 @@".  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is because I prefer to work through reviews in issue order,
not in file order; i.e. if there's a problem with the structure of some
API, I will fix issues with the tests and the code at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: glyph (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-8583996537367579331.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-17T01:32:00+00:00</updated><author><name>glyph (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-17:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I may have made my argument too strongly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can definitely see some advantages to using email. Having dealt with a
couple of your reviews written in this style now, I can appreciate its
subjective impact, at least a little. Personally I find it a wash with
the way that I'm doing things now.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your comment about feedback like "there are some coding standard issues"
is well-taken. This is a pretty crappy form of comment, and we should
try to keep that in mind ourselves and also educate other reviewers
about what constitutes a good comment. I don't think this actually has
anything to do with the tools, because I've gotten (and written) lots of
reviews that don't make that mistake.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite kind of review is where everything is phrased in terms of
FQPNs; there is a button in my editor which can (sort of) take me
directly to the definition of an FQPN, so it's a very quick copy/paste.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main point, though, is that these are both rough approximations of
what we actually want. You don't want to type into the middle of a hunk
of diff; I don't want to copy and paste an FQPN into some bespoke secret
elisp. We both want to abstractly indicate a region of changed code and
annotate it during the review process, then send those annotations back
to the author in a format where they can easily see them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can see how emailing commentary on diffs more closely approximates
this ideal for you. For me, it does not, and I prefer ticket comments
with module names in them. But let's not lose sight of the fact that
both experiences are terrible next to being able to push a button in
your editor and see the next feedback comment you have to deal with,
right next to the code that the feedback is on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a mechanism to jump directly to a region of code in emacs
based on a mangled / email-quoted diff, though, I'd be very interested
:).&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Posted by: Michael Hudson (noreply@blogger.com)</title><link href="http://code.mumak.net/2008/11/review-thoughts.html/#comment-893167848990395595.md" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-17T10:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Hudson (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:code.mumak.net,2008-11-17:2008/11/review-thoughts.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think that most of what glyph wants could probably be done with a
sufficiently advanced major mode for Launchpad style
review-amongst-quoted-diffs. Not that I'm going to write this any time
soon.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with the fancy web-based solutions -- have glyph or
jml tried any of them? I haven't -- is that you can't use emacs, of
course.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also don't have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; that much experience with Twisted's development
process yet -- hopefully that will change soon :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>